Ganesh Neelakanta

 $+91\ 9010999523 \mid \underbrace{\text{neelakantaganesh@gmail.com}}_{\text{https://github.com/neelakantaganesh23}} \mid \underbrace{\text{www.linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}}_{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakantaganesh23}} \mid \underbrace{\text{neelakantaganesh}}_{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}} \mid \underbrace{\text{www.linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}}_{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}} \mid \underbrace{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}}_{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}} \mid \underbrace{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}}_{\text{linkedin.com/in/neelakanta-ganesh}}$

OBJECTIVE

Proficient technical skills in SQL,Python Having experience in collecting, organizing, interpreting, data cleaning, and data visualization. Looking forward to exciting roles with opportunities to set and execute the vision in AI/ML. Ability to work independently

EDUCATION

CVR College of Engineering

Hyderabad, Telangana July. 2019 – May 2023

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication CGPA-8.24/10

Experience

Junior Data Engineer

June 2023 – Present

Anblicks

Hyderabad, Telangana

- Developed few applications using Streamlit, Snowflake, Azure and Snowpark
- Presented a knowledge exchange session on Azure AI Studio with organization
- Effectively communicated with team members to overcome challenges and obstacles, seeking assistance when faced with technical issues.
- Actively participated as a delegate representing my organization in multiple events held in Hyderabad.

Data Engineer Intern

Jan. 2023 - May.2023

• Gained practical experience in various technologies including Power BI, Data

Hyderabad, Telangana

- Gained practical experience in various technologies including Power B1, D Warehouse, Azure, ADF, SQL, Snowpark API and Snowflake.
- Designed and developed a robust ETL pipeline that efficiently extracts, transforms, and loads incremental retail sales data from various sources
- Employed change data capture (CDC) and CI/CD techniques to identify and process only the new or modified data, optimizing data processing efficiency

Projects

Anblicks

Footlocker | Databricks, Generative AI, LLMs, FastAPI

July 2024 – Present

- We built application to remove licenses for inactive users within an organization is the project's goal to reduce application license costs.
- Azure Datalake Gen2 was utilized to store user metadata, including logs and personal data, while Azure Data Factory served as a platform for data integration between Snowflake and ADLS Gen2.
- Effectively coordinated projects across different time zones, collaborating with colleagues in both the US and India

CBRE-SnowPatrol | Python, Azure Data Lake, ADF, Machine Learning, Snowflake

May 2024 – June 2024

- We built application to remove licenses for inactive users within an organization is the project's goal to reduce application license costs.
- Azure Datalake Gen2 was utilized to store user metadata, including logs and personal data, while Azure Data Factory served as a platform for data integration between Snowflake and ADLS Gen2.
- Effectively coordinated projects across different time zones, collaborating with colleagues in both the US and India

SnowGOV | Python, Streamlit, Snowflake

June 2023 – April 2024

- Designed and implemented a comprehensive cloud-based resource management application using Snowflake and Streamlit.
- Developed interactive UI components to configure organizational parameters, create projects and environments, onboard users, and monitor costs
- The objective of this project is to develop an App that provides GUI-based governance features for managing the Snowflake environment.

Retail Sales Data Analysis | Azure Databricks, Python, ADF, SQL, Azure, Power BI March 2023 - May 2023

- Designed and developed a robust ETL pipeline that efficiently extracts, transforms, and loads incremental retail sales data from various sources.
- Employed change data capture (CDC) techniques to identify and process only the new or modified data, optimizing data processing efficiency.

Ultra-Compact imprecise 4:2 Compressor, Multiplier | CNTFET, Cadence

Jan 2023 – June 2023

- Developed innovative solutions for ultra-compact circuit design using CNTFET technology and approximate computing methodologies
- Highly effective imperfect 4:2 compressor and multiplier circuits were designed, with performance trade-offs and energy savings in mind.

Agrivigilance Security System for Detection | Machine Learning, OpenCV, Python June 2022 – Dec 2023

• Successfully enhanced agricultural security by developing and implementing an innovative hardware solution that minimizes crop losses due to animal damage and unauthorized access

SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, Snowpark, SQL, Pyspark, C

Technologies: Snowflake, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, Azure Data Factory, Power BI, Databricks

Libraries: Snowpark, streamlit, pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, OpenCV

Softskills: Communication, Presentation, Team Management, Problem Solving, Business value

Achievements

Hackathon Winner: SnowGov won the hackathon organized by Anblicks in partnership with Snowflake.

Rookie Award: I was honoured with Rookie Award at Anblicks Euphoria 2024 in recognition of my passion towards my work and my contribution to anblicks.

Achieved 21 Badges at Google Cloud Skills Boost: Spent most of my time with acquiring skills for my career growth

GCP Certified: Google Cloud 30 days challenge organized by GDSC clubs at college

Certifications

SnowPro Core Certification BUILD 2023 LLM Bootcamp Generative AI Fundamentals Database Programming with SQL Data science and Machine Learning track

Extra Curricular

- Actively participated in Microsoft Azure, Snowflake, AWS events which helps me to gain insights and to make corporate network with industry experts
- Interested in making IPOs investments, Over 50 IPOs had been invested.
- Quantitative Financing and Investment Banking
- Dedicated to continuous self-improvement, I actively seek out knowledge through reading self-help books and staying informed about industry trends

LINKS

Github:// neelakantaganesh23 LinkedIn://ganeshneelakanta

GoogleDevelopersProfile:// ganeshneelakanta

Medium://ganeshneelakanta Accredible://ganeshneelakanta Credly:// ganeshneelakanta